Guide to the Abraham Yates, Jr. papers, 1604-1825 [bulk 1760-1796]
The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.
- ALPHABETICAL LIST
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter to the Honble Robert Morris Esq., Superintendent of Finance;. Transmitting a Return for the Month of Sept. and also a Bill of Exchange. 1 p. small quarto, dated Albany, October 4, 1792
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter in his autograph to the Hon'bl James Duane & Ezra L'Hommedieu
    An interesting letter giving the substance of a conversation with Col. Hamilton. "I told him I thought the Financier had too much Power already and that Congress had better curtail him - but I thought Congress could not now take it up as he had done Congress such Essential service". 3 p. quarto, dated Albany, Oct. 19, 1782.
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr. draft of letter to. the Honbl. Robert Morris Esq., Superintendent of Finance, Philadelphia. "I am exposed to Inconveniences by having devoted three whole Years to Service of the public for which I have not hitherto with repeated Soli, November 4, 1782
    Also another copy of the same in a different handwriting. 2 p. folio.
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of his letter to Judge David Howell, Refers to the pamphlets of Dr. Price & the Abbe De Mably & the five points discussed in them, relative to the dangers threatening the Government. 2 p. quarto, dated Albany, August 29, 1785
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Abraham G. Lansing (probably), "I am making ready to Dine at the Gover's where I expect to see Coll, Monson and some others that probably will give me information of the Loan office". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio dated New, February 1, 1786
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Abm. G. Lansing, Post Master, Albany. Mentions Duer, Bancker, Osgood- & refers to the Oath of Office which he was required to take. autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, dated New York, March 1, 1786
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr. draft of letter In his autograph & signed by him, to William Smith, Long Island. Expressing sympathy on account of his illness & extending an invitation to himself & wife to make a visit in Albany. 2 p. quarto, dated Albany, July 27, 1786
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr. draft of letter In his autograph to - -, Refers to canvassing the voices for Senator. 1 p. folio, dated New York, June 2, 1787
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Abraham G. Lansing. "Antifederal Business is Carried on in this County with spirit. New York they are all in a panic with the adoption of Massachusetts". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Poughkeepsie, February 28, 1788
  - Yates, Abraham, Munr., to Abraham G. Lansing. Relating to politics. "They Honour me with being at the head of that party and to that end have been all the scurrilous publications". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Senate Room, Poughkeepsie, March 14, 1788
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Abraham G. Lansing. "Wether We will breaks up this week and when is made uncertain by Mr. Duane, Lawrence and Van Der Bilt arrived here (it is said) for the express purpose of Carrying the Legislator to New York". autograph lette, March 18, 1788
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr, addressed to Abm, G. Lansing Esq, Albany. Reports a conversation held with Col. Hamilton. "I told him rather than to adopt the Constitution I would risk a government of Jew, Turk or Infidle. I told him the government that were agreea, May 28, 1788
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Abraham &. Lansing, Refers to the Assembly Election & the hopes of the Federalists for the adoption of the Constitution. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated New York, June 1, 1788
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Abraham G. Lansing Esq., Post Officer, Albany. Refers to the adoption of the Constitution. "The members from this place seem determined not to adopt (without previous amendments) tho all the others should. What steps th, June 15, 1788
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr. addressed to Abm. G, Lansing Esq., Post Master, Albany. Refers to his suit against Claxton, the printer, & gives some of his ideas in regard to the education of children. autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, June 23, 1788
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Abraham G. Lansing Esq., Albany. "Whilst I am writing advise is brought that New Hampshire had adopted the New Constitution which bread such an inattention to the Business the Southern Members to write letters to Virgin, June 25, 1788
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., 2 drafts of letter in his autograph to the Governor. Refers to the news from New Hampshire & the Loan from Holland. "L'Hommedieu last Monday mentioned that he had form a strong Federal (Dr. Tillotson) that the Anties went upon a sup, June 27, 1788
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Abraham G. Lansing, Post Master, Albany. "It appears that the Anties are neither to be frowned or flattered out of their opinion". Also refers to the lean made in Holland & the proposal to make a new loan. Autograph let, June 29, 1788
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., document, part of it in his autograph. Endorsed: -"Minuter of the Convention which formed the Constitution of the State of New York". Refers to the manner of carrying on elections for Senators the duties of the Governor & other, undated [1777]
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr. A statement of his reasons for voting for the new Constitution, tho he was opposed to it in principle. Also, an acknowledgment of the receipt of the above declaration, signed by Ezra L'Hommedieu, Egbert Benson & Alexander Hamilton. A, dated August 8, 1788
    Also, Document in autograph of Abraham Yates Junr., a. copy of the above. 2 p. quarto.
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr. Also signed by John H. Cook & John De Wandelaer as witnesses. In autograph of Abm. G. Lansing. William Angell's warrant of Attorney to Abraham G. Lansing. Also, Document signed by Abraham Yates Junr., John H. Cook & John De Wandelaer, dated February 25, 1791
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter, to Aaron Burr This draft was apparentlysent to Robert Yates Esq, for his approval before sending the letter to Burr. Refers to the case against Mr. Ten Broeck, for which Burr was Yates' attorney, 2 p. quarto, dated, April 24, 1791
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr. draft letter to Dirck Ten Broeck Esq, Relative to the withdrawal of Yates' suit against Ten Broeck. "As the Injury is of a public as well as private nature It is my intention Directly to publish the Certificate". 1. quarto, dated Alb, June 18, 1791
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr. (Mayor) An Act of the Corporation, of the City of Albany. "allowing & permitting a Ferry Stairs to be erected in the Wharf opposite to Mark Lane". D. S. 1 p. folio, dated in Common Council, June 21, 1793
  - Yates, Christopher P., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. and in his absence to Matthew Viescher Esq. in Albany. Interesting letter asking assistance from the Albany Committee. "We have just recd. Intelligence by Express from Oneida that a large Body of Indi, June 8, 1776
  - Yates, Christopher P., addressed to Henry Glen Esq., A. D. Q. M. Genl. Schenectady. Declining to accept a seat in either House of the Legislature for family reasons, "As to Major Frey I know his Sentiments on the Subject so well that I am well convinced h, April 7, 1781
  - Yates, Christopher P. addressed to the Hon. Abraham Yates Esq. in Congress, New York. Interesting letter in relation, to the adoption of the Constitution. The Federalists appear much elated by the adoption of the Constitution in N. Hampshire. We are got t, June 27, 1788
  - Yates, Christopher P., addressed to Hon. Abraham Yates Esquire, New York. Interesting letter referring to a heated argument between Mr. Lansing and Mr. Hamilton, in the Constitutional Convention, on the necessity of the existence of the State governments, June 30, 1788
  - Yates, Christopher P., addressed to Mr. John Pourteous, Referring to three Judgments against some small estates. A. L, S, 1 p. quarto, dated August 14, 1791
  - Yates, Joseph C. (Governor), addressed to Christopher Y. Lansing Esquire, Albany, Subscribing for 500 shares of stock of the Commercial Bank, 1 page quarto
    L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated Schenectady, May 29, 1825.
  - Yates, Peter, Document signed by him, Johannis Saml. Pruyn, Matthew Visscher, Christopher P. Yates & others. Indenture & Copy of Mortgage Bond of house and lot in the second ward of the city of Albany. 5 p. folio, dated November 16, 1767; dated May 30, 1769; dated April 10, 1776
  - Yates, Peter W, ä addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Leonard Gansevoort & John D. P. Ten Eyck, Esquires, Pokeepsy, Referring to a petition presented to the Legislature by Mary Elmendorph. Autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, dated New York, January 21, 1788
  - Yates, Richard. Order on Messrs. Sargent Chambers & Co. of London to pay one hundred pounds to Evert Bancker, Endorsed by Evert Bancker. A. D. S. oblong strip, dated New York, March 23, 1774
  - Yates, Robert, Complaint of Thomas Winn, through Robert Yates, his attorney, against Christian Alli for selling him a bay stallion under false pretences and asking damages to the extent of 18 pounds. D. 2 p. folio, dated January, 1767
  - Yates, Robert, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Chairman of the Committee, Albany. Introducing Col. Flemming, "a gentleman appointed by this Congress adjutant General to the Army under the Command of General Schuyler". autograph letter signed 1 p., September 6, 1775
  - Yates, Robert Intersting paper giving extracts from the resolves of the Committee of Safety for the State of New York in reference to the purchase of wheat for the use of the Continental Army and the exemption of certain coopers from militia duty. D. S. 2, October 29, 1776
  - Yates, Robert, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Member of Congress at New York. Refers to the Philadelphia Convention. "Additional Rules have since been entered into, one of which strictly prohibits the communication of its business until the final, June 1, 1787
  - Yates, Robert. Ordering the Sheriff to discharge from custody Thomas Lewis Spotten & James Spotten of the town of Lansingburg. 3 p. large folio, dated November 5, 1790
  - Yates, Robert, Discharge of Joseph Tobias, who had been confined in the Albany jail. D. S. 2 p. folio, dated March 3, 1791